Inventory of the Harrison Holt Riddleberger Papers 1874-1902
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
{Special Collections, University of Virginia Library}
Harrison Holt Riddleberger Papers, 1872-1902.
Special Collections, College of William and Mary
Mss. 65 R44
689 items.
Papers, 1872-1902, of and concerning Harrison Holt Riddleberger, a federal and state political figure, including correspondence, newspaper clipping, speeches, and notes for speeches.
Harrison Holt Riddleberger.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
Gift: 576 items, 1950.
Purchased: 1 item, 07/28/1977.
Gift: 110 items 2003.
Custodial History
Harrison Holt Riddleberger Papers were maintained by the staff of Duke University Library, North Carolina, until they were transferred, at the family's request, to Manuscripts and Rare Books Department, Swem Library, College of William and Mary in ca. 1950. An addition to the collection was made in 2003.
Biographical/Historical Information
Harrison Holt Riddleberger was born in Edinburg, Shenandoah County, Virginia in October 1844. He served in the Confederate cavalry. Riddleberger was a newspaper editor, studied law and practiced in Woodstock, Virginia. He was a member of the Virginia House of Delegates, 1871-1875; Commonwealth's attorney of Shenandoah County; a Democratic Party elector; and was elected as a Readjuster to the United States Senate where he served from 1883-1889. Riddleberger died 24 January 1890.
Scope and Content Information
This collection contains letters and other papers, 1872-1902, of H. H. Riddleberger (1844-1890) of Woodstock, Virginia who retained the titles of member of the House of Delegates, 1871-1875; State Senator, 1879- 1882; and U.S. Senator, 1883-l889. Among the correspondents are: William Mahone, William E. Cameron, Winfield S. Hancock, Roscoe Conkling, Robert Toombs, Fitz-John Porter, John W. Daniel, and John Goode. There are letters from Riddleberger to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger and to their children.
Arrangement
Organization
This collection has been organized into two Series: 1. Letters and 2. Miscellaneous Material.
Arrangement
Series 1, containing the bulk of the collection, are a series of letters arranged in chronological order by date. Those items with no date or an unknown date are placed at the end of the series. Series 1, Subseries are separated by year. Everything else remaining in the inventory was then classified as miscellaneous papers and sorted into various Sub-series, found at the end of the finding aid.
Index Terms
Persons:
Mahone, William, 1826-1895.; Cameron, William Evelyn, 1842-1927.; Hancock, Winfield Scott, 1824-1886.; Conkling, Roscoe, 1829-1888.; Toombs, Robert Augustus, 1810-1885.; Porter, Fitz-John, 1822- 1901.; Daniel, John W. (John Warwick), 1842-1910.; Goode, John, 1829-1909.
Geographical Names:
Virginia--Politics and government--1865-1898
Occupations:
Readjuster Party of Virginia.
Components List
  Series 1: Letters
- Letters, 1874-1893, n.d. (Box 1-2, Folder 1-29)
  - Letters, 1874., 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Geo. R. Calvert, New Market, to Harry H. Riddleberger, 16 Feb. 1874., 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - M.L. Walton, U. of Virginia, to [Dear Capt.], 21 Nov. 1874., 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letters, 1875., 5 items. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Wm. Mahone to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 12 Jan. 1875., 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Wm. Mahone to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 14 Jan. 1875., 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Wm. Mahone to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 16 May 1875., 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Wm. Mahone to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 6 June 1875., 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Wm. Mahone to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 2 Sept. 1875., 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letters, 1876., 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Wm. Mahone to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 26 March 1876., 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Wm. Mahone to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 31 Oct. 1876., 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letters, 1877., 10 items. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - J.E. Stewart, Luray to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 15 March 1877., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 12 June 1877., 1 item. LS. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 19 Aug. 1877., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 28 Aug. 1877., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 31 Aug. 1877., 1 item. LS. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 20 Sept. 1877., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 28 Sept. 1877., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 8 Dec. 1877., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 10 Dec. 1877., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Warrant of appointment as District Deputy Grand Master, Masonic order, to H.H. Riddleberger, 12 Dec. 1877., 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letters, 1878., 10 items. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Robert Toombs, Westhampton, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 27 Jan. 1878., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 2 March 1878., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 30 March 1878., 1 item. LS. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 10 June 1878., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 15 July 1878., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 20 July 1878., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 24 July 1878., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 24 July 1878., 1 item. L. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Wm. Mahone, Old Point, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 25 July 1878., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 7 Oct. 1878., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letters, 1879., 19 items. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Wm. Mahone to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 13 March 1879., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Wm. Mahone, Richmond, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 2 April 1879., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 22 April 1879., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 27 April 1879., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 19 May 1879., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 30 June 1879., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 8 Aug. 1879., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Wm. Mahone to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 22 Aug. 1879., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Wm. Mahone to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 4 Sept. 1879., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Wm. Mahone to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 11 Sept. 1879., 1 item. L. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 16 Sept. 1879., 1 item. L. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - J. G. Cannon, to [Dear Genl.], 16 Sept. 1879., 1 item. Copy. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 18 Sept. 1879., 1 item. L. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 24 Sept. 1879., 1 item. L. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 26 Sept. 1879., 1 item. L. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 30 Sept. 1879., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Wm. Mahone to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 5 Oct. 1879., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Wm. Mahone to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 14 Oct. 1879., 1 item. L. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Wm. Mahone, Richmond, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 13 Nov. 1879., 1 item. LS. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letters, 1880., 37 items. (Box 1, Folder 5-7)
    - Wm. Mahone to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 1880., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - A. Fulkerson, Richmond, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 21 Feb. 1880., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - A. Fulkerson, Richmond, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 21 Feb. 1880., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Wm. Mahone, Whig office, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 19 March 1880., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Wm. Mahone, Whig office, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 31 March 1880., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Wm. Mahone to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 13 April 1880., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Wm. Mahone to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 26 April 1880., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Wm. Mahone to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 28 April 1880., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Wm. Mahone, Richmond, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 14 May 1880., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Wm. Mahone, Richmond, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 4 June 1880., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Wm. Mahone to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 21 June 1880., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - T. T. Fauntleroy Jr., Richmond, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 29 June 1880., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 19 July 1880., 1 item. L. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Wm. Mahone, Richmond, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 20 July 1880., 1 item. L. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - T. T. Fauntleroy Jr., Richmond, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 20 July 1880., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - T.T. Fauntleroy Jr., Winchester to Father, 26 July 1880., 1 item. L. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Wm. Mahone to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Aug. 1880 [?]., 1 item. L. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Wm. Mahone to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 15 Aug. 1880 [?]., 1 item. L. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Wm. Mahone (note), 21 Aug. 1880 [?]., 1 item. L. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 24 Sept. 1880., 1 item. L. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Wm. Mahone, Richmond, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 24 Sept. 1880., 1 item. L. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 1 Oct. 1880., 1 item. L. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 1 Oct. 1880., 1 item. L. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - J.H. Chamberlayne, Richmond, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 6 Oct. 1880., 1 item. L. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Wm. Mahone, Richmond, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 14 Oct. 1880., 1 item. L. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Wm. Mahone, Richmond, to Paul, 14 Oct. 1880., 1 item. L. Copy. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Wm. Mahone, Philadelphia, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 24 Oct. 1880., 1 item. L. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Wm. Cameron, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 5 Nov. 1880., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Wm. Cameron, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 14 Nov. 1880., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 18 Nov. 1880., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - W. S. Hancock, Gov. Island to Editor, 22 Nov. 1880., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 25 Nov. 1880., 1 item. L. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Wm. Cameron, Petersburg to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 1 Dec. 1880., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 2 Dec. 1880., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Wm. Mahone to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 4 Dec. 1880., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Wm. Cameron, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 27 Dec. 1880., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Wm. Cameron, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 30 Dec. 1880., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Letters, 1881., 79 items. (Box 1, Folder 8-11)
    - Letters, Jan.-April 1881., 13 items. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - W. Mahone, Richmond, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 12 Jan. 1881., 1 item. L. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - J.B. Heiskell, Memphis, Tenn. to [?], 17 Jan. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 15 Feb. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 18 Feb. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 23 Feb. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 9 March 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Wm. Cameron to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 14 March 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Wm. B. Mathews, Washington, to Wm. Cameron, 19 March 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Wm. Cameron, Petersburg to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 21 March 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Wm. Cameron to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 22 March 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Wm. Cameron, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 5 April 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Wm. Cameron to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 15 April 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Wm. Cameron, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 27 April 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Wm. Mahone, Washington, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 17 May 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Wm. Cameron, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 19 May 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Wm. Mahone, Washington, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 23 May 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Wm. Mahone, Washington, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, June 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Wm. Mahone to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 5 June 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Wm. Mahone, Richmond, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 17 June 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - W. C. Elam, Richmond, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 18 June 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Wm. Mahone, Richmond, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 28 June 1881., 1 item. L. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - H.H. Riddleberger, Woodstock, to Mahone, 17 July 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Drafts and notes, 14 Oct. 1881., 6 items. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Items concern H.H. Riddleberger's challenge to a newspaper editor.
    - George D. Wise, Richmond, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 20 Oct. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 24 Oct. 1881., 1 item. L. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - H.H. Riddleberger, Woodstock to editor, 31 Oct. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Frank Alfriend, Richmond, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 10 Nov. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Samuel Kimberly, Norfolk, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 12 Nov. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - George R. Calvert, New Market, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 14 Nov. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - J.B. Snodgrass, Martinsburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 14 Nov. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - E. C. Brooke, Cuckoo, Va., to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 15 Nov. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Frank Alfriend, Washington, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 16 Nov. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Frank Alfriend, Washington, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 17 Nov. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - T.T. Fauntleroy Jr., Richmond, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 24 Nov. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - G. R. Calvert, Richmond, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 28 Nov. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - A. H. Lindsay, Portsmouth, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 29 Nov. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - J. W. Bell, Culpeper, Va., to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Dec. 1881 [?]., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - R. A. Richardson, Marion, Va. to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 1 Dec. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - John S. Wise, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 2 Dec. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - E. W. Early, Charlottesville, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 7 Dec. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - J. H. Yager, Gordonsville, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 8 Dec. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - D. W. Maphis, Mt. Olive, Va., to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 9 Dec. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - J. H. Clements, Portsmouth, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 11 Dec. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - G. Calvert & L. S. Walker, Woodstock, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 12 Dec. 1881., 1 item. Telegram. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - F. H. Pierpont, Fairmont, W. Va., to Dr. Wing, 12 Dec. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - J. Robinson, Portsmouth to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 12 Dec. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - J. C. Van Auken, Washington, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 12 Dec. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - E. E. Portlock, Lynchburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 14 Dec. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - G. C. Wedderburn, Washington, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 14 Dec. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - M. H. Berry, Hagerstown, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 14 Dec. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - E. J. Cunningham, Georgetown, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 14 Dec. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - S. M. Yost, Staunton, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 14 Dec. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - E. J. Harvie, Washington, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 14 Dec. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - S. D. Hawkins, Baltimore, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 14 Dec. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Blair, Crockett, etc. Wytheville to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 14 Dec. 1881., 1 item. Telegram. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - George R. Calvert, New Market, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 15 Dec. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - D. W. Whiting, Alexandria, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 15 Dec. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - W. W.Douglas, Washington, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 15 Dec. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - J. M. Hines, Washington, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 15 Dec. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - J. W. Houck, Baltimore, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 15 Dec. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - H. C. Nelson, Washington, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 15 Dec. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - J. L. Hamilton, Lexington, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 16 Dec. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - C. S. Roller, Ft. Defiance, Va., to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 19 Dec. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - John Paul, Harrisonburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 21 Dec. 1881., 1 item. Telegram. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - O.L. Rhodes, Baltimore, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 21 Dec. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - D. A. Grimsley, Culpeper, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 22 Dec. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Wm. Mahone to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 23 Dec. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - T. T. Fauntleroy, Winchester, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 26 Dec. 1881., 1 item. ALS. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Letters, 1882, 11 items. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Wm. Mahone, Washington, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 1882 [?]., 1 item. ALS. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Roscoe Conkling, N.Y., to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 7 Jan. 1882., 1 item. ALS. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Wm. Mahone, Washington, to Duff Green, 7 Feb. 1882., 1 item. ALS. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Wm. Mahone, Washington, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 2 March 1882., 1 item. ALS. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Wm. Mahone, Washington, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 13 March 1882., 1 item. ALS. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Lewis A. Leonard, Cincinnati to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 15 March 1882., 1 item. ALS. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Office No. American Review, N.Y. to [?], April 1882., 1 item. L. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Wm. Mahone, Washington, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 19 May 1882., 1 item. ALS. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Wm. Mahone, Washington, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 17 July 1882., 1 item. ALS. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Wm. Mahone, Washington, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 8 Aug. 1882., 1 item. ALS. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - A. D. Shepard, N.Y., to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 17 Nov. 1882., 1 item. ALS. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Letters, 1883., 19 items. (Box 2, Folder 13-14)
    - Wm. Mahone, Washington, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 1 Jan. 1883., 1 item. ALS. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Wm. Mahone, Washington, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 8 Jan. 1883., 1 item. ALS. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Wm. Mahone, Washington, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 23 March 1883., 1 item. ALS. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 30 March 1883., 1 item. ALS. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 15 April 1883., 1 item. ALS. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 24 April 1883., 1 item. ALS. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Wm. Mahone, Washington to A. Broaddus, 28 April 1883., 1 item. ALS. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - H.H. Riddleberger, Woodstock, to A. W. Harris, 20 June 1883., 1 item. ALS. Apparent draft of the letter. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Wm. Mahone, Washington, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 3 July 1883., 1 item. ALS. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 15 July 1883., 1 item. ALS. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 16 July 1883., 1 item. ALS. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 17 July 1883., 1 item. ALS. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 20 July 1883., 1 item. ALS. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Fitz-John Porter, Morristown, N. J., to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 22 July 1883., 1 item. ALS. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 26 July 1883., 1 item. ALS. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Woodstock, to Fitz-John Porter, 18 Aug. 1883., 1 item. ALS. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Wm. Mahone, Petersburg, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 30 Sept. 1883., 1 item. ALS. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - E.J. Porter, Morristown, N.J., to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 22 Nov. 1883., 1 item. ALS. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - James R. Young, Washington, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 22 Dec. 1883., 1 item. ALS. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Letters, 1884., 15 items. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Edward J. Rowe, N.Y., to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 27 Jan. 1884., 1 item. Telegram. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Peter Schanlan, Jersey City, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 27 Jan. 1884., 1 item. Telegram. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - W. J. Hughes etal, Philadelphia, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 28 Jan. 1884., 1 item. Telegram. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Dan Omadigan, Quarantine, Mo., to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 28 Jan. 1884., 1 item. Telegram. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - James O'Donohoe, Biloxi, Miss., to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 28 Jan. 1884., 1 item. ALS. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - R. N. Mills, M.D., Elmira, N.Y., to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 5 Feb. 1884., 1 item. ALS. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - F.J. Porter, Morristown, N.J., to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 15 March 1884., 1 item. ALS. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - John T. Lyle, Richmond, Va., to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 5 May 1884., 1 item. ALS. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Wm. Mahone, Richmond, to Harrison Holt Riddleberger, 16 Aug. 1884., 1 item. L. (Box 2, Folder 15)